<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>wade&#39;s blog</title>
  <subtitle>various microblogs, ramblings, fun thematic gatherings of links, and other blog posts.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/" />
  <updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://wade-cheng.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>wade cheng</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>the tomato method</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/blog/pomodoro/" />
    <updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.com/blog/pomodoro/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I&#39;ve been trying the pomodoro method recently. I believe the canonical set
    of instructions is
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;tight&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;25 minute work session&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;5 minute break&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;repeat, extending the break to 20 minutes every four cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    The idea is to cut down on burnout and be able to dedicate time to full,
    100% concentration. The name comes from the Italian word for tomato, which
    is what the original inventor&#39;s kitchen countdown timer was presumably
    shaped like.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I think the idea is pretty cool. In a vaccum, I have the issue of
    hyper-focusing when things get interesting, which leaves me feeling drained.
    Or I don&#39;t want to start work I perceive as stressful. So I usually end up
    taking long breaks or procrastinating work. With the tomato idea, I can
    instead tell myself &quot;pspspsps it&#39;s only a short work time it won&#39;t be an
    extended length of Bad don&#39;t worry you&#39;re so okay&quot; which is helpful for
    motivation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    There exists another interesting perspective toward this rigid timeline,
    which I&#39;ll explain via a quick side example. A friend once mentioned to me
    that they always take the stairs, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; when an elevator is
    available, because it&#39;s one less decision they have to make. Wowee! Cool!
    This principle applies to this work-rest scheduling issue for me. Even if I
    feel like I want more or less time to work than 25 minutes, or if I feel
    like I want more or less time to rest than five, I take the predetermined
    time anyways. There&#39;s some inefficiency where working more or resting less
    gets more work done, but I gladly trade that for staving off burnout and the
    mitigating the undesired sections of the contingency table: wanting to work
    less or rest longer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I track the time bounds with my analog watch, which is great because I just
    look for the minute hands reaching the top and bottom of the watch face. I
    usually skip long breaks or make them 30 minutes long to fit everything into
    watch-face-compatible blocks. I often also hide the clock widget on my
    laptop&#39;s taskbar so I&#39;m not peeking at it too often&amp;mdash;I can just look at
    my watch instead. I find I work best when there&#39;s as few moving parts (not
    controlled by me) on my screen as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    As a final note, I use the Hank Green&#39;s Focus Friend app to additionally
    motivate me to keep on track. It also helps me get out of an unproductive
    rut by setting a quick five minute &quot;focus&quot; period and using that to just
    stand up and start moving. That is, anytime I&#39;m taking a too-long break,
    perhaps after a meal or before I leave the study lounge to go get ready
    before bed, etc etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>on hyperlink styling</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/blog/on-hyperlink-styling/" />
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.com/blog/on-hyperlink-styling/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I&#39;ve changed my opinion on how hyperlinks should be styled throughout my
    life, and I&#39;ve recently been thinking about it again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    First, some history and some context. I like small, cozy, lightweight
    websites! My first links were probably unstyled, along with the rest of the
    webpage, but this was probably changed quite quickly. I think the blue on
    white is tacky, and the clicked-purple on white more so. They then became
    black to match the rest of the body text in color, in part because I don&#39;t
    think it really matters if you&#39;ve already visited a page or not, or maybe I
    just don&#39;t like things changing out from under me. And then set it to
    un-underline on-hover to boot. Cute!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    The most recent development in my link styling steals from Matthew
    Butterick&#39;s Practical Typography. He
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://practicaltypography.com/how-to-use.html&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;But
    underlining is nothing more than an odious typewriter habit, held over on
    websites because of inertia. It was tolerable in 1994 when web browsers
    could do so little. But not today, when they can do so much,&quot; as well as &quot;Of
    course, the main reason hyperlinks have historically been overstyled is
    because generating clicks on those links is essential to internet
    advertising. Here, you will find no advertising&amp;mdash;just us readers. The
    design is tailored accordingly.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Well, that&#39;s quite heartwarming. I&#39;m charmed! The current revision of my
    stylesheet implements his link style&amp;mdash;an indeed unobtrusive hollow
    circle superscripting the link, where the link body fades into an accent
    color once hovered&amp;mdash;but with a purple take on the accent color instead
    of his maroon.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I really do have to reiterate how heartwarming the rationale is behind this
    style. And I do indeed feel that the resulting text is considerably less
    noisy than before. And it feels softer! The lazy fade in of the pastel
    accent color is quite cozy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    But finally, to the downsides. Visibility. Ehhhh, probably not the greatest
    now. Butterick
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://practicaltypography.com/underlining.html&quot;&gt;alleges&lt;/a&gt; that
    plenty large sites no longer use underlining, but this seems mostly only
    strictly true in the display regions of these sites where links may read as
    buttons instead. The current
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scottylabs.org/&quot;&gt;ScottyLabs website&lt;/a&gt; is a clear
    example. However, when in the body of actual content (see: Wikipedia as a
    canonical example), these sites instead turn to underlining on hover while
    maintaining a colored link.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, not sure how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I don&#39;t quite like setting links in an accent color, because I enjoy the
    idea of being able to read my site just fine after running it through a
    grayscale printer. Much of my undergrad has been morally supported by having
    paper to leaf through and annotate. It&#39;s grounding.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I&#39;m not sure about the Butterick Method. How does one know where a link
    starts, if only the end is delimited? Additionally, I&#39;m not convinced of the
    attractiveness of adding a circle to delimit on the left side. If it&#39;s
    placed at the same height, it looks a bit like a googly-eyed alien, I&#39;m not
    sure what to think about if it goes near the baseline (as if like
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quotation_mark&quot;&gt;Dutch quotations&lt;/a&gt;), and either way it&#39;s a bit noisy and bubbly and messes up the word
    spacing and eh.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Maybe I&#39;ll even go back to the original all-black method of styling, clutter
    be damned.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll see how my tastes change in these coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>typography</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/blog/typography/" />
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.com/blog/typography/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I love typography!!! Massive fan of making things look nice. I&#39;ve just added
    lead-in small caps to the start of these content pages and enabled oldstyle
    figures for when I might want them later. (For now, these are the ones that
    look like this:
    &lt;span class=&quot;oldstyle&quot;&gt;1234567890&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Also, I&#39;ve through this just discovered that EB Garamond actually supports a
    lot of OpenType features after all. The
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://googlefonts.github.io/ebgaramond-specimen/&quot;&gt;typography specimen&lt;/a&gt;
    linked from the Google Fonts page is quite pretty. Unfortunately and
    ironically, the Google Fonts binary for the font doesn&#39;t actually bundle
    these features. This site statically hosts the full (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wade-cheng.com/assets/eb-garamond/OFL.txt&quot;&gt;OFL-license-licensed&lt;/a&gt;) font from
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/octaviopardo/EBGaramond12&quot;&gt;https://github.com/octaviopardo/EBGaramond12&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    A really nice resource on many things typography is Matthew Butterick&#39;s
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;https://practicaltypography.com/&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>neeeerd</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.com/blog/neeeerd/" />
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.com/blog/neeeerd/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I have a habit of, often when gaming, calling someone who knows how to do
    anything but the most obvious and beginner thing, a nerd. Aw man this guy
    just killed me by executing the basic combo relevant to their character,
    their bread and butter? Oh my god this guy&#39;s a nerd :0
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    The connotation is important, though: it&#39;s not making fun of the person at
    all, I think it just makes life more happy to be easily impressed. Maybe
    they came into the game playing that character for the first time, and they
    had enough prior experience to just get it right with zero effort. Or maybe
    this is a beginner who spent long hours of practice to now be able to show
    it off. No matter what, even if it&#39;s something that&#39;s relatively simple to
    me, now, hey. That was pretty cool, anyways.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is about League of Legends.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>