<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>wade&#39;s blog</title>
  <subtitle>various microblogs, ramblings, fun thematic gatherings of links, and other blog posts.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/" />
  <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/</id>
  <author>
    <name>wade cheng</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>typography</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/blog/typography/" />
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/blog/typography/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I love typography!!! Massive fan of making things look nice. I&#39;ve just added
    lead-in small caps to the start of these content pages and enabled oldstyle
    figures for when I might want them later. (For now, these are the ones that
    look like this:
    &lt;span class=&quot;oldstyle&quot;&gt;1234567890&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Also, I&#39;ve through this just discovered that EB Garamond actually supports a
    lot of OpenType features after all. The
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://googlefonts.github.io/ebgaramond-specimen/&quot;&gt;typography specimen&lt;/a&gt;
    linked from the Google Fonts page is quite pretty. Unfortunately and
    ironically, the Google Fonts binary for the font doesn&#39;t actually bundle
    these features. This site statically hosts the full (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/assets/eb-garamond/OFL.txt&quot;&gt;OFL-license-licensed&lt;/a&gt;) font from
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/octaviopardo/EBGaramond12&quot;&gt;https://github.com/octaviopardo/EBGaramond12&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    A really nice resource on many things typography is Matthew Butterick&#39;s
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://practicaltypography.com/&quot;&gt;https://practicaltypography.com/&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>neeeerd</title>
    <link href="https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/blog/neeeerd/" />
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://wade-cheng.is-a.dev/blog/neeeerd/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    I have a habit of, often when gaming, calling someone who knows how to do
    anything but the most obvious and beginner thing, a nerd. Aw man this guy
    just killed me by executing the basic combo relevant to their character,
    their bread and butter? Oh my god this guy&#39;s a nerd :0
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    The connotation is important, though: it&#39;s not making fun of the person at
    all, I think it just makes life more happy to be easily impressed. Maybe
    they came into the game playing that character for the first time, and they
    had enough prior experience to just get it right with zero effort. Or maybe
    this is a beginner who spent long hours of practice to now be able to show
    it off. No matter what, even if it&#39;s something that&#39;s relatively simple to
    me, now, hey. That was pretty cool, anyways.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is about League of Legends.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>